{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Impignorate","incorrectAnswers":["Dipthong","Deipnophobia","Erf"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'to pawn or mortgage something'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Black Thursday","incorrectAnswers":["Dark Wednesday","Blue Monday","Grizzly Friday"],"question":"What was the name of the stock market crash that began the Great Depression in 1929?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Keyser Söze","incorrectAnswers":["Keyser Wilhelm","Keyser Gundogan","Keyser Rommel"],"question":"In the movie \"The Usual Suspects\", who might have been the killer named Verbal Kint?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Copenhagen","incorrectAnswers":["Milan","Athens","Munich"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Denmark?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Dylan","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","Eric Clapton","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American musician released the album 'Blood on the Tracks'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Tiber","incorrectAnswers":["The Nile","The Thames","The Seine"],"question":"King Ancus Marcius is said to have built the Sublician Bridge, the first bridge across which river in the 7th century B.C.?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["The UK","Germany","Austria"],"question":"Where is Eurodisney?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Illinois","incorrectAnswers":["Ohio","Indiana","Michigan"],"question":"Which US state is home to Willis Tower, McDonald's Museum and Abe Lincoln's Tomb?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Olivia Wilde","incorrectAnswers":["Sophia Loren","Madonna","Jacqueline Bisset"],"question":"Which actress has starred in both 'The O.C'. and the 2013 film 'Her'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Homophonic pairs","incorrectAnswers":["Synonyms","Antonyms","Doublets"],"question":"What is the term for a two words that are pronounced the same but have different meanings?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Shaped pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Stuffed pasta","Tubular pasta","Strand pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is casarecce?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Princess Diana","incorrectAnswers":["Queen Elizabeth II","Camilla Parker Bowles","Sarah Ferguson"],"question":"In 1982, which member of the British royal family gave birth to Prince William?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"George A. Custer","incorrectAnswers":["Erwin Rommel","Hannibal","William T. Sherman"],"question":"Who was defeated at the Battle of Little Bighorn?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mauritius","incorrectAnswers":["Myanmar","Iceland","Fiji"],"question":"Port Louis is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Owl","incorrectAnswers":["Squirrel","Frog","Horse"],"question":"In Greek mythology, what animal is associated with Athena?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince","incorrectAnswers":["Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone","Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban","Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'It was nearing midnight and the Prime Minister was sitting alone in his office, reading a long memo that was slipping through his brain without leaving the lightest trace of meaning behind.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Liver","incorrectAnswers":["Goose","Fat","Force"],"question":"What does the 'foie' mean in 'foie gras'? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gaston","incorrectAnswers":["The Evil Queen","Ursula","Maleficent"],"question":"What is the name of the villain in Beauty and the Beast?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Manila","incorrectAnswers":["Quezon City","Cebu City","Makati"],"question":"What Is The Capital Of The Philippines?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Dallas Cowboys","incorrectAnswers":["Dallas Crew","Dallas United","Dallas Bengals"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Dallas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hinduism","incorrectAnswers":["Jainism","Buddhism","Sikhism"],"question":"Which is the oldest religion in the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Anthony Blunt","incorrectAnswers":["Frank Johnson","Christopher Linberg","Harold Walker"],"question":"In 1979 which English art historian was exposed as a one-time Soviet spy and stripped of his knighthood?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Bee Hummingbird","incorrectAnswers":["Pigeon","Great Horned Owl","Ostrich"],"question":"What is the smallest bird in the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Uruguay","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","West Germany","France"],"question":"Which Country Won The First Football World Cup? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Rembrandt","incorrectAnswers":["Vermeer","Van Gogh","Monet"],"question":"What Dutch master painted 64 self-portraits?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Croatia","incorrectAnswers":["Libya","Italy","Ecuador"],"question":"In which country would you find the City of Dubrovnik?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Stigmata","incorrectAnswers":["Holy Molies","Psalms","Anaschsim"],"question":"Which word refers to the appearance of wounds in places that correspond to the crucifixion wounds of Christ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kenny Rogers & Dolly Parton","incorrectAnswers":["Sonny and Cher","Michael and Janet Jackson","Bob Dylan and Joan Baez"],"question":"Which Duo Had A Hit With The Song \"Islands In The Stream\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Poland","Spain","Sweden"],"question":"In the 17th century which country started taxing beards?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Red River","incorrectAnswers":["The Blue River","The Yellow River","The Green River"],"question":"What is the name of the river that runs through Canada's Manitoba province and empties into Lake Winnipeg?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"A Breve","incorrectAnswers":["A Minim","A Semibreve","A Crotchet"],"question":"What is the name of the musical note that is equal in length to two whole notes?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Cornett","incorrectAnswers":["Drum","Bongo","Ukelele"],"question":"Which of these is a brass instrument?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Bull","incorrectAnswers":["A Billy","A Cob","A Hob"],"question":"What is the word for a male yak?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Purple","Yellow","Blue"],"question":"What Colour Does Litmus Paper Turn When Dipped In Acid?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Stringed","incorrectAnswers":["Percussion","Woodwind","Brass"],"question":"What type of instrument is a double bass?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Uruguay","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","West Germany","Argentina"],"question":"Which country won the 1950 FIFA World Cup, hosted in Brazil?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Qatar","incorrectAnswers":["Mauritius","Peru","Cambodia"],"question":"Doha is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Maltese Falcon","incorrectAnswers":["The Adventures of Robin Hood","Being There","Pirates of the Caribbean"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Sam Spade'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Raiding","incorrectAnswers":["Exploration","Migration","Trade"],"question":"What is the name of the Viking practice of sailing off to unknown lands in search of riches and glory?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Southpaw","incorrectAnswers":["Goofy","Regular","Orthodox"],"question":"What Do You Call A Boxer Who Leads With Their Right? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kate Bush","incorrectAnswers":["David Bowie","John Lennon","George Michael"],"question":"Which British recording artist released the studio album 'The Dreaming'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Tenochtitlan","incorrectAnswers":["Tlatelolco","Teotihuacan","Tzintzuntzan"],"question":"What is the name of the Aztec capital city?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Stomach","incorrectAnswers":["Heart","Liver","Lungs"],"question":"Gastritis affects the __________.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Pine Tree","incorrectAnswers":["Oak Tree","Maple Tree","Birch Tree"],"question":"Which type of tree is known for its hard wood and conical shape?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Salvador Dali","incorrectAnswers":["Pablo Picasso","Francisco Goya","Diego Velazquez"],"question":"Which Spanish artist famously created a lobster telephone?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Grease","incorrectAnswers":["Gangs of New York","The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly","Terms of Endearment"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Sandy Olsson'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ruble","incorrectAnswers":["Euro","Swiss Franc","Yen"],"question":"What is the name of the monetary unit that is equal to 100 kopecks?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Vino della casa ","incorrectAnswers":["Vino del campo","Vino della mansione","Vino del domin"],"question":"How would you say 'house wine' in Italian?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Acid reflux","incorrectAnswers":["Heart disease","Pneumonia","Gastritis"],"question":"What is the medical term for the condition that causes heartburn?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"1 Year","incorrectAnswers":["1 Day","28 Days","1 Month"],"question":"How long does it take for the Earth to orbit the Sun?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tricolor","incorrectAnswers":["Red, White, and Blue","The Golden Fleece","The Union Jack"],"question":"What is the name of the French flag?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mary Shelley","incorrectAnswers":["Bram Stoker","Edgar Allen Poe","Jane Austen"],"question":"Who was the author of Frankenstein?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Donald J. Trump","incorrectAnswers":["Benjamin Harrison","George W. Bush","James Monroe "],"question":"Who was the 45th president of the USA, in term during the period 2017–2021?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Lamb","incorrectAnswers":["A Maggot","A Caterpillar","A Fry"],"question":"What is a baby sheep known as?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Sow","incorrectAnswers":["A Nanny","A Soar","A Lioness"],"question":"A female hedgehog is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Greece","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Egypt","China"],"question":"In which country did red figure pottery flourish from the 6th to the 4th century B.C.?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Grateful Dead","incorrectAnswers":["The Band","The Allman Brothers Band","Jefferson Airplane"],"question":"Which band includes the musician Jerry Garcia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Arabic","incorrectAnswers":["Hebrew","Egyptian","Italian"],"question":"What is the official language of Egypt?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Feet","incorrectAnswers":["Antennae","Nose","Anus"],"question":"What Does A Butterfly Use To Taste?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"It Won't Be Soon Before Long","incorrectAnswers":["Songs About Jane","Hands All Over","Overexposed"],"question":"Which was Maroon's 5 second studio album?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Great Gatsby","incorrectAnswers":["For Whom the Bell Tolls","To Kill a Mockingbird","The Catcher in the Rye"],"question":"Which 1925 classic is said to capture all the romance and glitter of the Jazz Age?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1959","incorrectAnswers":["1953","1965","1971"],"question":"In which year was Ben-Hur first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Mare","incorrectAnswers":["A Worker","A Nanny","A Cow"],"question":"What would you call a female zebra?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Wednesday","incorrectAnswers":["Thursday","Friday","Saturday"],"question":"What day follows 'Ash' in the name of the first day of Lent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Sow","incorrectAnswers":["A Doe","A Ewe","A Cow"],"question":"What is the word for a female hog?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Renaissance","incorrectAnswers":["Impressionism","Primitivism","Fauvism"],"question":"The painting \"Creation of Adam\" by Michelangelo is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Niger","incorrectAnswers":["Kyrgyzstan","Belize","Israel"],"question":"Niamey is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"What is said is done","incorrectAnswers":["I came, I saw, I conquered","Let them hate so long as they fear","Honey, I'm home!"],"question":"What is the meaning of the Latin phrase 'Dictum factum'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Apples","incorrectAnswers":["Oranges","Grapes","Pineapple"],"question":"What is the main fruit ingredient in a Waldorf salad?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Iron","incorrectAnswers":["Copper","Gold","Aluminum"],"question":"Magnetite, which is noted for its natural magnetism, is an important ore of which metal?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Reincarnation","incorrectAnswers":["Immortality","Purgatory","Afterlife"],"question":"What is the term used for the belief that the soul is reborn in a new form after death?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cheese","incorrectAnswers":["Tomatoes","Beans","Chili"],"question":"What is the main ingredient in queso dip?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"A greengrocer","incorrectAnswers":["A farmstall","A fresh provider","A produce stand"],"question":"What is a retailer of fresh vegetables and fruits in England called?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dante Alighieri","incorrectAnswers":["Giovanni Boccaccio","Agatha Christie","Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Vita Nuova'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"C-Class","incorrectAnswers":["Civic","T35","DS19"],"question":"Which of these is a model of car made by Mercedes-Benz?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Who released the iconic album 'Thriller'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Isaac Asimov","incorrectAnswers":["Ursula K. Le Guin","Philip K. Dick","Stephen King"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Robots of Dawn'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bean Curd ","incorrectAnswers":["Seitan","Quorn","Whitejelly"],"question":"What Is Tofu Also Known As?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Shoulder blade","incorrectAnswers":["Ribs","Collar Bone","Kneecap"],"question":"What is the common name for the scapula?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Oscar Wilde","incorrectAnswers":["Charles Dickens","G. K. Chesterton","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Happy Prince and Other Tales'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Fred Perry","incorrectAnswers":["Roy Emerson","Rod Laver","Andre Agassi"],"question":"Who was the first to win the career grand slam of tennis (all four major championships)?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Lyndon B Johnson","incorrectAnswers":["Gerald Ford","Richard Nixon","Thomas Jefferson"],"question":"Who took over from John F Kennedy after he was assassinated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Rams","incorrectAnswers":["The Blades","The Clarets","The Tigers"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Derby County?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Andromeda","incorrectAnswers":["Hercules","Ursa","Orion"],"question":"What is the name of the closest large spiral galaxy to our galaxy?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bahamas","incorrectAnswers":["Vanuatu","Peru","Kiribati"],"question":"Nassau is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Ronald Reagan","incorrectAnswers":["John F. Kennedy","Abraham Lincoln","Barack Obama"],"question":"Before becoming a politician, which US President was a Hollywood actor?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Modulate Demodulate","incorrectAnswers":["Modern Demograph","Modular Emitter","Mono Demo"],"question":"In computing what term does the word modem come from?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The World Is Not Enough","incorrectAnswers":["Octopussy","Casino Royale","For Your Eyes Only"],"question":"Which Bond film features the character of Dr Christmas Jones?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Vincent Price","incorrectAnswers":["Bela Lugosi","Christopher Lee","Boris Karloff"],"question":"Which actor did the voice-over on the Michael Jackson song 'Thriller'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Arnold Schwarzenegger","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Douglas","Dustin Hoffman","Andy Serkis"],"question":"Which actor played the role of The Terminator in The Terminator?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Edwyn Collins","incorrectAnswers":["The Waitresses","Rockwell","The Heights"],"question":"'A Girl Like You' was a one hit wonder in 1994 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Trial","incorrectAnswers":["Gulliver's Travels","Carmen","I Am Legend"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'Someone must have been telling lies about Joseph K., for without having done anything wrong he was arrested one fine morning.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bull","incorrectAnswers":["Horse","Dolphin","Eagle"],"question":"In what animal form did Zeus seduce Europa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Rue","incorrectAnswers":["Avenue","Boulevard","Lane"],"question":"What French word means 'to feel sorry for' and means 'street' in France?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Jordan","incorrectAnswers":["Monaco","Syria","Iran"],"question":"King Abdullah was assassinated in 1951. Of which country was he king?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Soccer","Golf","Athletics"],"question":"With what sport is Gabriela Sabatini associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1973","incorrectAnswers":["1963","1949","1984"],"question":"When was the first mobile phone conversation?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A charm","incorrectAnswers":["A paddling","A bevy","A flight"],"question":"What is the word for a group of goldfinches?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Chanel","incorrectAnswers":["Gucci","Dior","Prada"],"question":"What luxury fragrance brand 'No.5' eau de parfum?","difficulty":"easy"},